Isaac M. Jordan – Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom IsaacJordan95@gmail.com

https://isaacjordan.me https://uk.linkedin.com/in/ijordan https://github.com/isaac-jordan

Summary

Professional software engineer with 8 years experience in large and small enterprise environments building innovative products aiming to be market leaders. Experienced in a variety of languages and technology stacks, most recently with C#, TypeScript, React, and Angular.

Work Experience

G-Research - Europe's leading quantitative finance firm

London, UK

Software Engineer [TypeScript, React, Angular, C#]

Oct 2021 - July 2024

- Created and iterated upon new tools for live monitoring of global trading, for example rejected trade analysis.
- Designed and implemented a new process and DSL for mass managing external connections with multi-person approval and an audit trail, allowing for a 10x scale-up of connection types.
- Refined my team's development processes, moving towards a more flexible kanban model, reducing code review turnaround time, and running regular retrospectives.

AWS (Amazon CodeGuru Profiler)

London, UK

Software Development Engineer II [TypeScript, React, Kotlin, AWS]

Sep 2019 - Oct 2021

- Developed a new product with a global team, such as simplified profiling visualisations, onboarding workflows, and new APIs to correlate data across AWS services. Wrote the first public blog post.
- Took on an informal engineering team lead role, mentoring other engineers through projects and regularly improved and simplified development and operational processes. E.g. introduced Kanban and simpler prioritisation discussions, follow-the-sun on-call rotas, safer launch processes, weekly dashboard reviews, and reusable infrastructure libraries (removing over 10k lines of code).
- Took ownership over the console (front-end) infrastructure and codebase, ensuring a high quality bar as new engineers took on front-end work and the service extended to 5 new AWS regions. Personally improved page performance by 50% and reduced bundle size by 20%.

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer II / I / Intern [Java, TypeScript, React, AWS] Sep 2017 - Sep 2019

- Integrated my team's video rendering API with a public Amazon Advertising product. Utilised AWS Lambda/DynamoDB/S3 for a new micro-service mediator with automated alarming, along with new TypeScript/React components.
- Launched a new programmatic video advertising program and increased ad performance by 10x in 6 months through rigorous A/B experimentation, exceeding our team goal of \$500k sales.
- Improved my team's development and release processes over time, e.g. introduced SonarQube for month-on-month code quality improvements, and new tools to track the team's operational load.
- Internship: Created a patent-awarded prototype application to convert existing video content into personalisable videos in a fast (real-time) and automated fashion, using a Java/OpenCV pipeline.

TBR Global Chauffeuring

Glasgow, UK

Software Developer (Intern, followed by Part-Time) [C#, MVC.NET, JavaScript] Jun 2015 - May 2016

- Cut manual ingestion time by 95% by preprocessing data using OpenAddressesUK and Google APIs.

Chi Squared Innovations

Remote

Software Developer (Part-Time) [Python, Django, JavaScript, d3.js]

Sep 2014 - Jun 2015

Education

University of Glasgow

Glasgow, UK

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science (First Class)

2013 - 2017

- Received top-of-class prize in Year 3, and first prize at Glasgow University Hackathon 2015.